<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Motion Planning on Amir Yazdani</title>
    <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/tags/motion-planning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Motion Planning on Amir Yazdani</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://amir-yazdani.github.io/tags/motion-planning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk-Aware Planning for Patient Fall Prevention</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/project/risk_aware_planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/project/risk_aware_planning/</guid>
      <description>In order to assist the patient efficiently, we develop a risk-aware planning framework which finds the best manipulation plan that minimizes the fall risk probability with minimum robot effort. We view the risk-aware planning problem from the perspective of probabilistic inference and solve it as a multi-objective optimization problem. For the fall risk objective, we use a linear combination of expected value and CVaR to minimize the overall risk of fall while avoiding even low probabilities of high fall risks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Manipulation Planning</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/project/pam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/project/pam/</guid>
      <description>In this project we introduce a patient assistant mobile (PAM) robot to monitor patient behavior and provide a cost-effective physical presence to continuously observe a patient and the environment to prevent falls.
Many common objects found inside hospital rooms and personal dwellings have legs (e.g. walkers, tables, chairs, equipment stands). For a mobile robot operating in such environments, safely maneuvering these objects without collision is essential. Since providing the robot with dynamic models of all possible legged objects that may exist in such environments is not feasible, autonomous learning of an approximate dynamic model for these objects would significantly improve manipulation planning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manipulation Planning of A Box Using A Mobile Robot</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/project/push_planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/project/push_planning/</guid>
      <description>Mobility is one of the most important factors that contributes to quality of life. Each year, about 35% of individuals over age 65 experience one or more falls. Falls are the third leading cause of chronic disability worldwide6. In this project, we tried to address the concerns with home falls with a low-cost, intelligent mobile robot that will provide mobility aids, such as a walker, in the event that it determines that risk of fall is high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safe Motion Planning in Shared Autonomy</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/project/safety_hri/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/project/safety_hri/</guid>
      <description>As human and robot collaboration become more intimate, and more intelligent robots are being used in both healthcare and manufacturing environments, the safety of humans working closely with companion or co-robots is becoming a challenging issue. As a result, there is a great need for developing improved control algorithms and better guidelines to allow humans and robots to safely work together in a synergistic fashion. The nature of human variability requires the robot to be able to learn and adapt to these changes while maintaining safety in the presence of an often unpredictable human worker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fault-Tolerant Motion Planning</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/project/ft_motion_planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/project/ft_motion_planning/</guid>
      <description>In this project we focused on making the motion planning of the robots fault-tolerant. We started with the simple Pseudo inverse approach to making the joint trajectory planning of planar redundant serial robots the fault tolerant. We made a 4-DOF planar robot (TaArm) to do the experimental studies to show the performance of the proposed method.
 End-effector’s linear velocity of the manipulator. The failure occurs at tf = 15s and the simulation time is 20s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collision-Free Optimal Path Planning</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/project/mpc_path_planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/project/mpc_path_planning/</guid>
      <description>This project focuses on the optimal path planning of redundant planar serial robots, while avoiding obstacles within its workspace. A synergy-based algorithm between convex optimization, disjunctive programming and receding horizon is employed to the end of achieving advantages such as finding the global optimum solution and low computational time.
This algorithm can handle both static and dynamic obstacles due to its replanning scheme. It has been implemented on redundant serial robots, parallel robots, mobile robots and a group of mobile robots.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>