<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Amir Yazdani on Amir Yazdani</title>
    <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Amir Yazdani on Amir Yazdani</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics Model Learning and Manipulation Planning for Objects in Hospitals Using a Patient Assistant Mobile (PAM) Robot</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/iros2018-pam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/iros2018-pam/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An abstract presented in NOIRS 2018 symposium</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/post/noirs2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/post/noirs2018/</guid>
      <description>


  

&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://amir-yazdani.github.io/img/noirs.jpg&#34; /&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amir presented in 2018 National Occupational Injury Reduction Symposiums (NOIRS 2018) with the title of
“Changing Perceptions of Robotics in Industry: Recent  Accomplishment in Safety and Injury Risk Reduction”.
He discussed what are the old, current and future solution for injury reduction in human-robot collaboration
and mentioned that there will be a new generation of collaborative robots, he names them “intelligent collaborative robots”,
that they have human biomechanics, ergonomics, and safety included in motion perception, planning and control algorithms
of collaborative robots. He reviewed the most cutting-edge researches in ergonomics and safety in HRC/HRI and introduces
the current challenges in this area of research. He also suggested several new research ideas and opportunities for
both robotics and safety and health communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pdf version of his presentation is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://amir-yazdani.github.io/files/NOIRS2018-AmirYazdani.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Neural Gas Network Approach for Obtaining The Singularity-Free Workspace of 3-DOF Planar Parallel Manipulators</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/imeche2016-pgngn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/imeche2016-pgngn/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Motion Planning for Parallel Robots Via Convex Optimization and Receding Horizon.</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/advrobotics2016-optimal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/advrobotics2016-optimal/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Pose Estimation in Telemanipulation</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/projects/pose_estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/projects/pose_estimation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Human posture estimation has been a challenging research problem and many solutions has been suggested for different applications. Mainly, marker-based motion capture system and markerless camera-bases systems are the most common methods to estimate human posture. Marker-based solutions are usually more accurate however they require a long preparation time for setting up parkers and calibration of mocap systems. Markerless are more convenient since they does not requires attaching markers on human body. Both of those methods are based on using cameras and have many limitation in real applications.
with the recent developments in physical human-robot interaction, estimating human posture is a demanding task specially in ergonomics and safety analysis, and adaption of robot motion based on human posture and motion.
In this project we propose a novel method to estimate human posture in telemanipulation. We believe that in physical interaction between human and the robot, only knowing the robot&amp;rsquo;s trajectory is adequate to estimate the human&amp;rsquo;s posture. We model the problem as a partially-observable dynamic model and use filtering and smoothing approaches to solve the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PAM: A Patient Assistant Mobile Robot for Fall Prevention</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/projects/pam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/projects/pam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this project we introduce a patient assistant mobile (PAM) robot to monitor patient behavior and provide a cost-effective physical presence to continuously observe a patient and the environment to prevent falls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many common objects found inside hospital rooms and personal dwellings have legs (e.g. walkers, tables, chairs, equipment stands). For a mobile robot operating in such environments, safely maneuvering these objects without collision is essential. Since providing the robot with dynamic models of all possible legged objects that may exist in such environments is not feasible, autonomous learning of an approximate dynamic model for these objects would significantly improve manipulation planning. Thus, we have developed a probabilistic algorithm that learns pre-categorized object models using minimal force and motion interactions between the robot and object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We account for multiple manipulation strategies by formulating the manipulation planning as a mixed-integer convex optimization problem. The proposed manipulation framework considers the hybrid control system comprised of i) choosing which leg to grasp, and ii) continuous applied forces to move the aid.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Design and Fabrication of a 4-DOF Quattrotaar Parallel Robot with Singularity-Free Workspace by ABC and PSO Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/modares2016-quattrotaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/modares2016-quattrotaar/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Motion Planning of Redundant Planar Serial Robots Using A Synergy-Based Approach of Convex Optimization, Disjunctive Programming and Receding Horizon</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/imeche2016-optimal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/imeche2016-optimal/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Experimental Study on The Failure-Tolerant Control of a Redundant Planar Serial Manipulator Via Pseudo-Inverse Approach</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/icrom2015-fault/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/icrom2015-fault/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and Kinematic Analysis of a 4-DOF Serial-Parallel Manipulator for a Driving Simulator</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/ijr2015-simulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/ijr2015-simulator/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workspace Determination of Planar Parallel Robots via Progressive Growing Neural Gas Network</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/icrom2014-pgngn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/icrom2014-pgngn/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design, Development, Dynamic Analysis and Control of a 2-DOF Spherical Parallel Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/icrom2014-agile2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/icrom2014-agile2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Modeling and Computed Torque Control of a 3-DOF Spherical Parallel Manipulator</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/icrom2014-agile3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/icrom2014-agile3/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VirSense: a Novel Haptic Device with Fixed-Base Motors and a Gravity Compensation System</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/indrobots2014-virsense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/indrobots2014-virsense/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and Kinematic Analysis of a 4-DOF Serial-Parallel Manipulator for Urban Bus Driving Simulator</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/icrom2013-simulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/publication/icrom2013-simulator/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
