<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HRI on Amir Yazdani</title>
    <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/tags/hri/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HRI on Amir Yazdani</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://amir-yazdani.github.io/tags/hri/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DULA: A Differentiable Ergonomics Model for Postural Optimization in Physical HRI</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/talk/rss2021_r4p/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/talk/rss2021_r4p/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited Talk: Ergonomically Intelligent Teleoperation Systems</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/talk/inria/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/talk/inria/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posture Estimation and Optimization in Ergonomically Intelligent Teleoperation Systems</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/talk/hri_pioneers2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/talk/hri_pioneers2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk-Aware Planning for Patient Fall Prevention</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/project/risk_aware_planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/project/risk_aware_planning/</guid>
      <description>In order to assist the patient efficiently, we develop a risk-aware planning framework which finds the best manipulation plan that minimizes the fall risk probability with minimum robot effort. We view the risk-aware planning problem from the perspective of probabilistic inference and solve it as a multi-objective optimization problem. For the fall risk objective, we use a linear combination of expected value and CVaR to minimize the overall risk of fall while avoiding even low probabilities of high fall risks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Posture Optimization in Teleoperation</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/project/pose_optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/project/pose_optimization/</guid>
      <description>Although teleoperation is a promising alternative to avoid injuries in high-risk tasks, awkward postures are still a primary contributor to works-related musculoskeletal disorders in teleoperation. An ergonomically intelligent teleoperation system could reduce risk by providing feedback for postural correction. In this project, we introduce a novel framework for postural optimization in teleoperation that benefits from common risk assessment tools in ergonomics and provides online postural correction as well as optimal initial posture correction for a teleoperator according to the type of teleoperation task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Posture Estimation in Teleoperation</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/project/pose_estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/project/pose_estimation/</guid>
      <description>Human posture estimation has been a challenging research problem and many solutions has been suggested for different applications. Mainly, marker-based motion capture system and markerless camera-bases systems are the most common methods to estimate human posture. Marker-based solutions are usually more accurate however they require a long preparation time for setting up markers and calibration of MoCap systems. Markerless approaches are more convenient since they does not requires attaching markers on human body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safe Motion Planning in Shared Autonomy</title>
      <link>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/project/safety_hri/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amir-yazdani.github.io/project/safety_hri/</guid>
      <description>As human and robot collaboration become more intimate, and more intelligent robots are being used in both healthcare and manufacturing environments, the safety of humans working closely with companion or co-robots is becoming a challenging issue. As a result, there is a great need for developing improved control algorithms and better guidelines to allow humans and robots to safely work together in a synergistic fashion. The nature of human variability requires the robot to be able to learn and adapt to these changes while maintaining safety in the presence of an often unpredictable human worker.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>